{
    "id": "b254f1e901934283b773cc69a6103191",
    "title": "Linking Words Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He suffered many setbacks, …………………………. he persisted.",
            "description": "But is used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "but",
                "despite",
                "however"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. his illness, he looked cheerful.",
            "description": "Despite is a preposition. It is followed by a noun or ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "Although",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They fought hard, ……………………… they were defeated.",
            "description": "However is not a conjunction. It cannot connect two clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "but",
                "however",
                "despite"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She works hard …………………………., she does not earn much.",
            "description": "However is a transitional adverb. It does not connect two clauses. However follows a full stop or semicolon. ",
            "answers": [
                "but",
                "however",
                "though"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The party was fun …………………………, I went home early.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "despite",
                "but",
                "though",
                "however"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… trying hard, he could not move the table.",
            "description": "Despite is followed by a noun or ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "Though",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. I missed the bus, I still managed to reach on time.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "However",
                "Despite"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. their best efforts, they could not save her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "However",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctors tried hard ……………………………, they could not save her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "however",
                "though",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. suffering grievous injuries, he is hopeful of making a complete recovery.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "Though",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. she was the most deserving student, she did not get admission.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "However",
                "Despite"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. hard you may try, you will not succeed.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "However",
                "Though",
                "Despite"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}